Virgil M. Brand papers, 1889-1990
American Numismatic Society
Virgil M. Brand papers
1889 - 1990
Correspondence, financial records, legal documents, inventories, and auction catalogs relating to Chicago coin collector and brewery owner Virgil M. Brand and the disbursement of his estate.
Brand, Virgil M., 1862-1926
American Numismatic Society
22 cubic feet (5 boxes and approximately 150 loose items)
Biographical Note
Coin collector Virgil M. Brand (1862-1926) was born in Chicago, where he eventually worked as a bookkeeper in his father’s business, the Michael Brand Company Brewery. In 1899, after the death of his father, Brand formed the Brand Brewing Company with his two brothers, Horace L. Brand (1868-1962) and Armin W. Brand (d. 1946), and a cousin. He developed an interest in coin collecting in 1889, eventually amassing one of the greatest private collections of all time. In 1907 he formed the Chicago Coin Company, which was owned by Virgil and managed by Theophile Leon. The company closed in 1915, transferring its unsold inventory to Brand. Brand also served as president of the Chicago Numismatic Society. Brand did not leave a will, and upon his death his collection was inherited by his brothers, who began to sell off pieces during the 1930s. Tensions between the brothers eventually had to be resolved in probate court, and in 1937 the Brand estate was divided between them. The brothers continued to sell parts of the collection, but some coins were inherited by Armin’s daughter, Jane Brand Allen. Those coins were sold in a series of auctions conducted by Sotheby’s, Bowers & Merena, and Spink & Son during the 1980s.
Access
Collection open to all researchers.
Coins--Collectors and collecting; Coin dealers; Breweries--Illinois; Brand, Virgil M., 1862-1926; Brand, Armin W., d. 1946; Brand, Horace L., 1868-1962; Grommes, Bertha; Allen, Jane; Chicago Coin; Lake Shore Country Club; Correspondence; Inventories; Notebooks; Financial records; Legal documents; Notes; Estate records; Auction catalogs; Photographs; Appraisals (Records); Accession records; Chicago (Ill.)
Scope and Content Note
Materials directly from Virgil M. Brand include his accession and inventory books (32 bound volumes), a printed version of a paper he wrote, “The Objects of Coin Collecting” (1905), two letters to his brother Armin W. Brand along with a reply (1909), a small notebook with coin notations dating from 1907 to 1926, and Chicago Coin Company records. There are also records pertaining to his estate, including correspondence, financial records, legal documents, and an inventory of his library (1926-1937). Materials from after Virgil’s death include Armin W. Brand’s correspondence (1906-1910, bulk 1926-1946), much of it with his brother, Horace L. Brand, on topics such as coin sales, the sale of Brand Company Brewery, and real estate transactions. Along with the correspondence are notes, memoranda, and legal and financial materials. A good deal of correspondence has to do with a court case involving Lake Shore Country Club (1906-1910, 1927-1936). Also present are correspondence and financial records relating to the estate of Armin W. Brand (1946-1950), as well as correspondence and inventories relating to coins and other matters (1948-1967) from Armin Brand’s daughter, Jane Brand Allen. Also includes records pertaining to the estate of Mrs. Leon Harlan Walkins (Bertha Grommes), Jane’s aunt. There are also coin inventories and appraisals (1930s-1950s), auction catalogs from the sale of Brand coins (1983-1990), slides and photographs of Brand coins (late 1900s), rubber stamps used by Virgil M. Brand, and photocopies of Virgil M. Brand’s accession books.
  nnan0034
- Box 1
    nnan0034/c_75c308c1effffeff15cd6455ff67cc2d
  - 1. Coins: "The objects of Coin Collecting," Paper by Virgil M. Brand, 1905
  - 2. Coins: Collection of Virgil M. Brand, Ledger, Journal, 1907-1926
  - 3. Coins: Collection of Virgil M. Brand, Code book (alphabetical by denomination), Captions by B. G. Johnson compared with captions of Virgil M. Brand, 1926
  - 4. Coins: Inventory of Numismatic Library, 1944
  - 5. Coins: Literature purchases, boxes containing coins, plates etc., Curio purchases, list of coins taken from coin books, correspondence from B. Max Mehl, 1921
  - 6. Coins: Armin W. Brand's notes on the organization and location of the collection, 1930
  - 7. Coins: Armin W. Brand's Correspondence with Horace L. Brand, 1927-1936
  - 8. Coins: Armin W. Brand's Correspondence with Numismatists, 1926-1932
  - 9. Coins: Armin W. Brand's notes and memoranda, 1934-1941
  - 10. Coins: Notes on the division of Virgil M. Brand's collection (between Horace L. and Armin W. Brand), including corrections and missing numbers, 1932-34, 1941
  - 11. Coins: Armin W. Brand's record of sales including country, date of sale, total dollar amount, 1936-45
  - 12. Coins: Collection of Armin W. Brand 1936-1947, consignment to B. G. Johnson, summaries
  - 13. Jane Brand Allen's Correspondence re. Coins American Express, 1952-1956
  - 14. Jane Brand Allen's Correspondence re. Coins, Frank E. Burke, Jr., insurance, 1958-1959
  - 15. Jane Brand Allen's Correspondence re. Coins, L. S. Forrer, Ltd., 1948-1949
  - 16. Jane Brand Allen's Correspondence re. Coins, L. S. Forrer, Ltd., 1952-1955
  - 17. Jane Brand Allen's Correspondence re. Coins, Guaranty Safe Deposit Company and Newburgh Savings Bank, 1949-1959
  - 18. Jane Brand Allen's Correspondence re. Coins, Adolph Hess, 1950-1963
  - 19. Jane Brand Allen's Correspondence re. Coins, Hans Holzer, 1965-1967
  - 20. Jane Brand Allen's Correspondence re. Coins, New Netherlands Coin Company, Inc., 1951-1953
  - 21. Jane Brand Allen's Correspondence re. Coins, New Netherlands Coin Company, Inc., 1954-1965
  - 22. Jane Brand Allen's Correspondence re. Coins, Charles Russell and Company, 1953-1957
  - 23. Jane Brand Allen's Correspondence re. Coins, Hans M. F. Schulman, 1964-1967
  - 24. Coins: Jane Brand von Boecklin Allen's miscellaneous inventories, newspaper clippings
  - 25. Coins: Jane Brand Allen's Silver inventory, n. d.
  - 26. Coins: Inventories-Appraisals, Austria-Austrian Netherlands, Austria States
  - 27. Coins: Inventories-Appraisals, British Colonies, Asia, Africa. #British Colonies West Indies, Denmark, England, England Rar., France, Japan
  - 28. Coins: Inventories-Appraisals, Germany
  - 29. Coins: Inventories-Appraisals, "England", 1935. Reconsignment B. G. Johnson to B. A. Seaby
  - 30. Coins: Inventories-Appraisals by B. G. Johnson, "England Gold", "England Minor", "England Missing", 1930's
  - 31. Coins: Inventories-Appraisals by B. G. Johnson, "England Silver", 1934
- Box 2
    nnan0034/c_172b3282514f1d545b8121e74dcff7c6
  - 1. Coins: Inventories-Appraisals, "France Silver", 1930's
  - 2. Coins: Inventories-Appraisals, Ancient Greek and Roman Silver
  - 3. Coin Inventories: Consignment to B. G. Johnson, Reconsignment to Spink and Hess 1937-1938, "Ancient Greek Silver", "Ancient Greek Gold"
  - 4. Coins: Inventories-Appraisals, "India", Reconsignment to Spinks, 1936
  - 5. Coins: Inventories-Appraisals, "Italy and Papal", Consignment to B. G. Johnson, 1937-1947
  - 6. Coins: Inventories-Appraisals, Italy, Silver and Gold, Milan, Venice, Naples, Sicily, Papal, and small states
  - 7. Coins: Inventories-Appraisals, "Latin America and Mexico", 1936, Consignment to B. G. Johnson
  - 8. Coins: Inventories-Appraisals, "Netherlands Silver', 1937 (later consigned to Schulmann)
  - 9. Coins: Inventories-Appraisals, "Norway Gold, Minor Silver", 1930's
  - 10. Coins: Inventories-Appraisals, "Oceania Gold", 1930's
  - 11. Coins: Inventories-Appraisals, "Russia Gold", 1934
  - 12. Coins: Inventories-Appraisals by B. G. Johnson, "Scotland and Ireland Gold", "Scotland and Ireland Silver"
  - 13. Coins: Inventories-Appraisals by B. G. Johnson, Swiss Gold List, n. d.
  - 14. Coins: Inventories-Appraisals by B. G. Johnson, "Switzerland Gold", "Switzerland Minor", "Switzerland Silver", (later consigned to Boldwin, Seaby, Hurlistram)
  - 15Coins: Inventories-Appraisals by B. G. Johnson, "Transvaal Gold" (consignment to Johnson in 1935)
  - 16. Coins: Inventories-Appraisals by B. G. Johnson and Chapman, United States-"Territorial Gold of California", "Colorado", "L - Pieces, New Orleans Mint", 1934
  - 17. Coins: Inventories-Appraisals to B. G. Johnson, United States, 1935-1937
  - 18. Coins: Inventories-Appraisals, United States
  - 18A. Coins: Inventories-Appraisals, United States, 1935-1936
  - 19. Coins: Inventories-Appraisals, Hall Collection, 1932-1935
  - 20. Coins: Hall Collection, 1951-1956
  - 21. Coins: Inventories-Appraisals, Wurzbach Collection, 1936, 1951
  - 22. Jane Brand Allen's Coin Inventories: Hall and Wurzbach Collections, 1951-1957
  - 23. Coins: Inventories-Appraisals by B. G. Johnson, "Rarities", 1930's
  - 24. Coins: "Estate of Virgil M. Brand schedule "Coins", June 20th, 1926"
  - 25. Coins: Inventories-Appraisals, Estate of Armin W. Brand, 1947 (2 copies)
  - 26. Coins: Inventories of invoices A, D, E, I, M, N, P, S, V, X, n.d.
  - 27. Coins: Inventories-Appraisals, Miscellaneous
  - 28. October 13-26, 1926, Book no. 151, Operator no.15, nos. 1-11680
  - 29. October 12-20, 1926, Book no. 152, Operator no. 4, nos. 12001-18320
  - 30. October 13-20, 1926, Book no. 153, Operator no. 13, nos. 18321-24655
  - 31. October 15-26, 1926, Book no. 154, Operator no. 19, nos. 24656-30990
  - 32. October 11-23, 1926, Book no. 155, Operator no. 7, nos. 30991-37325
- Box 3
    nnan0034/c_4f22ef1245b3e66369d2e30cb9331478
  - 1. October 10-18, 1926, Book no. 156, Operator no. 2, nos. 37326-43590
  - 2. November 21-26, 1926, Book no. 157, Operator no. 5, nos. 43591-50205
  - 3. November 19, 1926, Book no. 158, Operator no. 13, nos. 50206-56540
  - 4. October 13-23, 1926, Book no. 159, Operator no. 12, nos. 56541-62875
  - 5. October 12-18, 1926, Book no. 160, Operator no. 5, nos. 62876-69210
  - 6. October 13-26, 1926, Book no. 161, Operator no. 14, nos. 69211-75545
  - 7. October 14-20, 1926, Book no. 162, Operator no. 6, nos. 75546-81880
  - 8. November 19-22, 1926, Book no. 163, Operator no. 2, nos. 81881-88285
  - 9. October 18-20, 1926, Book no. 164, Operator no. 24, nos. 88286-90280
  - 10. October 15-20, 1926, Book no. 165, Operator no. 21, nos. 90281-93850
  - 11. October 15-26, 1926, Book no. 166, Operator no. 20, nos. 93851-100815
  - 12. October 15-28, 1926, Book no. 167, Operator no. 17, nos. 100816-107780
  - 13. November 1-11, 1926, Book no. 168, Operator no. 28, nos. 4716-1-14188-1080 (folder title says: Book no. 168, operator no. 28, nos. 4716-1-4716-689)
  - 14. November 1-10, 1926, Book no. 169, Operator no. 24, nos. 15159 to 21528-2560
  - 15. Book no. 170, nos. 21528-2561 to 29560-105
  - 16. November 27, 1926, Book no. 171, nos. 29560-106 to 36731-63
  - 17. October 16, 1926, Book no. 172, Operator no. 23, nos. 107781-112995
  - 18. October 16-26, 1926, Book no. 173, Operator no. 22, nos. 112996-112995
  - 19. October 10-22, 1926, Book no. 174, Operator no. 18, nos. 118211-123425
  - 20. October 16-25, 1926, Book no. 175, Operator 25, nos. 123426-128640
  - 21. October 19-29, 1926, Book no. 176, Operator 2, nos. 128641-134715
  - 22. December 20-21, 1926, Book no. 250, Operator no. 13, nos. 134716-137351
- Box 4
    nnan0034/c_57e9bd37d2d36f4af8c87b25b4249a67
  - 1. Brand Papers: Virgil Brand's correspondence with Armin W. Brand, 1909
  - 2. Brand Papers: Armin W. Brand's correspondence with Horace L Brand, January to December, 1926
  - 3. Brand Papers: Armin W. Brand's correspondence with Horace L. Brand, January to October, 1927
  - 4. Brand Papers: Armin W. Brand's correspondence with Horace L. Brand, November to December 1927
  - 5. Brand Papers: Armin W. Brand's correspondence with Horace L. Brand, January to February, 1928
  - 6. Brand Papers: Armin W. Brand's correspondence with Horace L. Brand, March to August, 1928
  - 7. Brand Papers: Armin W. Brand's correspondence with Horace L. Brand. September to November 22, 1928
  - 8. Brand Papers: Armin W. Brand's correspondence with Horace L. Brand, November 23 to December, 1928
  - 9. Brand Papers: Armin W. Brand's correspondence with Horace L. Brand, January to June, 1929
  - 10. Brand Papers: Armin W. Brand's correspondence with Horace L. Brand, July to December, 1929
  - 11. Brand Papers: Armin W. Brand's correspondence with Horace L. Brand, 1930
  - 12. Brand Papers: Armin W. Brand's correspondence with Horace L. Brand, January to May, 1931
  - 13. Brand Papers: Armin W. Brand's correspondence with Horace L. Brand, June to December, 1931
  - 14. Brand Papers: Armin W. Brand's correspondence with Horace L. Brand, 1932-1933
  - 15. Brand Papers: Armin W. Brand's correspondence with Horace L. Brand, 1934-35
  - 16. Brand Papers: Armin W. Brand's correspondence with Horace L. Brand, 1936-1938, 1942-1946
  - 17. Brand Papers: Brandsville Fruit Farm Company, Armin W. Brand's correspondence with Horace L. Brand, 1926-1943
  - 18. Brand Papers: Gun cleaning compound (Ammonium Persulfate), Armin W. Brand's correspondence, 1941
  - 19. Brand Papers: Real Estate, Armin W. Brand's correspondence with Horace L. Brand, 1926-1927
  - 20. Brand Papers: Real Estate, Armin W. Brand's correspondence with Horace L. Brand, 1928-1929
  - 21. Brand Papers: Real Estate, Armin W. Brand's correspondence with Horace L. Brand, 1930-1931
  - 22. Brand Papers: Real Estate, Armin W. Brand's correspondence with Horace L. Brand, 1932-1933
  - 23. Brand Papers: Real Estate, Armin W. Brand's correspondence with Horace L. Brand, 1934-1944
  - 24. Brand Papers: Armin W. Brand's file: "Pending" (miscellaneous) includes: newspaper clippings, balance sheets, keys, receipts, ticket stub, notes, 2 poems by "Harry", and photographs, 1932-1944
  - 25. Brand Papers: Brand Brewing and Malting Co. bank statements, receipts, and bills, 1906-1934
  - 26. Brand Papers: Brand Brewing and Malting Co., correspondence, 1932-1938
  - 27. Brand Papers: Brand Company: Armin W. Brand's correspondence with Horace L. Brand, 1927-1930
  - 28. Brand Papers: Brand Company: Armin W. Brand's correspondence with Horace L. Brand, 1931-1941
  - 29. Brand Papers: Brand Company: Armin W. Brand's correspondence with Horace L. Brand, 1942-1946
  - 30. Brand Papers: Brand Company: Sale of Brewery Property, 1930-1943
  - 31. Brand Papers: Brand Company: Armin W. Brand's correspondence with Horace L. Brand re: Royal Brewing Company, 1933-1934
  - 32. Brand Papers: Brand Company: Properties 2542-44 Elston Avenue and Snow Street property, David L. Moss & Co. and Gould Co. leases, 1938-1946
  - 33. Brand Papers: Brand Company: Armin W. Brand's with Horace L. Brand re: Royal Brewing Company, 1933-1934
  - 34. Brand Papers: Brand Company: Alcohol (for the War Production Board), 1940-1944
  - 35. Brand Papers: Brand Company: Rental of brewery property to U. S. Government, 1940-1945
  - 36. Brand Papers: Brand Company: Equipment sale, 1941-1944
  - 37. Brand Papers: Brand Company: Description and plates of Brewery Company property (2530 Elston Ave.), 1943-1944
  - 38. Brand Papers: Brand Company report, 1931
  - 39. Brand Papers: Brand Company: Jane Brand von Boecklin Allen's correspondence with Horace L. Brand concerning the sale of part of Brand Company's coal yards, 1949-1950
  - 40. Coin cards - notes on cost, prices being asked for similar specimens, buyer's names (5 envelopes)
  - 41. Coins: Inventories-Appraisals, Foreign gold - Sweden, Rome, Portugal, Netherlands, Mexico, Malta & Rhodes, France, Denmark, Central America, Balkans, Asia Oriental, Mohammedan, Spain, Scotland & Ireland, British colonies - Asia, Austrian States, Austria Netherlands, Cananda & Newfoundland, England & Great Britain, British colonies & West Indies, Italy papal, Russia, 1935
  - 42. Coins: Inventories - Appraisals, foreign gold, silver, minor, France, 1930s
  - 43. Coins: Inventories - Appraisals, foreign, France, minor1930s
  - 44. Coins: Inventories - Appraisals, foreign gold, French provinces, 1935
  - 45. Coins: Inventories - Appraisals, foreign, Switzerland, 1930s
  - 46. Coins: Inventories - Appraisals, foreign silver, Switzerland, 1930s
  - 47. Coins: Inventories - Appraisals, foreign rarities, Denmark, 1930s
  - 48. Coins: Inventories - Appraisals, foreign, Balkans, 1930s
  - 49. Coins: Inventories - Appraisals, foreign silver, West Indies, 1930s
  - 50. Coins: Inventories - Appraisals, foreign gold, silver, minor, West Indies, 1930s
- Box 5
    nnan0034/c_bf4deddbb69f281f95d0ef38bea4da06
  - 1. Brand Papers: Brand Company: Tax case, July 1943 to January 1945
  - 2. Brand Papers: Brand Company: Legal and Financial documents, 1933
  - 3. Brand Papers: Brand Company: Lake Shore Country Club case: Armin W. Brand's correspondence with Horace L. Brand, 1906-1910
  - 4. Brand Papers: Lake Shore Country Club: Armin W. Brand's correspondence with Horace L. Brand, 1927
  - 5. Brand Papers: Lake Shore Country Club: Armin W. Brand's correspondence with Horace L. Brand, 1928
  - 6. Brand Papers: Lake Shore Country Club: Armin W. Brand's correspondence with Horace L. Brand, 1929
  - 7. Brand Papers: Lake Shore Country Club case: Armin W. Brand's correspondence with Horace L. Brand, 1930
  - 8. Brand Papers: Lake Shore Country Club case: Armin W. Brand's correspondence with Horace L. Brand, 1931
  - 9. Brand Papers: Lake Shore Country Club: Armin W. Brand's correspondence with Horace L. Brand, 1932-1935
  - 10. Brand Papers: Lake Shore Country Club: Armin W. Brand's correspondence with Horace L. Brand, 1936
  - 11. Brand Papers: Lake Shore Country Club: Armin W. Brand's correspondence with Robert and Erna Zeddies, 1930- 1936
  - 12. Brand Papers: Lake Shore Country Club: John H. S. Lee correspondence, 1927, 1928, and 1930
  - 13. Brand Papers: Lake Shore Country Club: John H. S. Lee correspondence, 1931
  - 14. Brand Papers: Lake Shore Country Club case: John H. S. Lee correspondence, 1932-1933
  - 15. Brand Papers: Lake Shore Country Club: John H. S. Lee correspondence, 1934
  - 16. Brand Papers: Lake Shore Country Club case: John H. S. Lee correspondence, January to September, 1935
  - Brand Papers: Lake Shore Country Club case: 17. John H. S. Lee correspondence, October 1935 to November 1936
  - 18. Brand Papers: Lake Shore Country Club case: Correspondence with attorneys, 1926-1936
  - 19. Brand Papers: Lake Shore Country Club case: Correspondence with Apprisers, Surveyors, Printers, Real Estate agents, Country clerks, etc.. 1926-1936
  - 20. Brand Papers: Lake Shore Country Club case: Court documents, 1930-1936
  - 21. Brand Papers: Lake Shore Country Club: Legal documents, 1909, 1936
  - 22. Brand Papers: Lake Shore Country Club: Maps and Plats
  - 23. Brand Papers: Lake Shore Country Club: Armin W. Brand's court notes of case, etc., 1926-1930
  - 24. Brand Papers: Lake Shore Country Club: Notes and Memoranda, 1925-1936
  - 25. Brand Papers: Lake Shore Country Club: Correspondence with the LSCC, 1926, 1934, and 1936
  - 26. Duplicates
  - 27. Brand Papers: Estate of Armin W. Brand, Deceased: correspondence and financial records of Jane Brand von Boecklin Allen and Frieda G. Brand, 1946-1948
  - 28. Brand Papers: Estate of Armin W. Brand: Jane Brand von Boecklin Allen's correspondence with Armin W. Brand's office, April to July, 1946
  - 29. Brand Papers: Estate of Armin W. Brand: Jane Brand von Boecklin Allen's correspondence with Armin W. Brand's office, August to December, 1946
  - 30. Brand Papers: Estate of Armin W. Brand: Jane Brand von Boecklin Allen's correspondence with Armin W. Brand's office, January 1947 to June 1950
  - 31. Brand Papers: Estate of Virgil M. Brand: Correspondence, Financial records, Legal documents, and notes, 1926-1937
  - 32. Brand Papers: Estate of Virgil M. Brand; Inventory of library, n.d.
  - 33. Brand Papers: Estate of Mrs. Leon Harlan Watkins (Bertha Grommes), 1976
- Ledgers and binders
  Virgil Brand kept an inventory of coin purchases in a set of ledgers that date from 1889 to 1925. In a large Main Ledger, he assigned a serial number to individual and sometimes groups of coins, and noted date of purchase, dealer, quantity, and cost. The serial numbers can be used to find further details about the coins in a set of Secondary Ledgers that give individual coin composition, country, denomination, date, cost, condition, mint marks, and description. In some cases, further details about individual coins that were given a serial number as a group in the Main Ledger can be found listed individually in one of four Extra Ledgers (Ex).
  The following key for can be used to determine the year a particular serial number was used (source: Virgil Brand: The Man and His Era, Q. David Bowers, 1983).
  Key
  1889 - 1-4512 (numbers 272 to 1,000 not used)
  1890 - 4513-4786
  1891 - 4787-5201
  1892 - 5202-5822 (numbers 5,823 to 9,999 were not used)
  1893 - 10,000-11,680 (numbers 11,681-12,000 were not used)
  1894 - 12,001-12,841
  1895 - 13,001-14,901 (numbers 12,842-13,000 were not used)
  1896 - 14,902-16,584
  1897 - 16,585-17,769
  1898 - 17,770-19,472
  1899 - 19,473-21,042
  1900 - 21,043-21,801
  1901 - 21,802-23,170
  1902 - 23,171-24,829
  1903 - 24,830-26,847
  1904 - 26,848-28,031
  1905 - 28,032-32,102
  1906 - 32,103-36,739
  1907 - 36,740-42,491
  1908 - 42,492-47,879
  1909 - 47,880-51,276
  1910 - 51,277-56,456
  1911 - 56,457-61,070
  1912 - 61,071-63,771
  1913 - 63,772-69,733
  1914 - 69,734-75,394
  1915 - 75,395-78,847
  1916 - 78,848-81,325
  1917 - 81,326-83,661
  1918 - 84,662-90,778
  1919 - 90,779-93,767
  1920 - 93,768-105,166
  1921 - 105,167-118,845
  1922 - 118,846-125,225
  1923 - 125,226-128,787
  1924 - 128,788-132,363
  1925 - 132,364-137,360
    nnan0034/c_d6671e6c28172457ab266eeb923acecc
  - Main Ledger, 1889-1925
  - Secondary Ledgers, 1889-1925
    Related Material
    A full set of photocopies are also available.
      nnan0034/c_bbf334fffb1919c2705c40eaab1239fc
    - 1 - 1-11,681 (1889-1893; numbers 272 to 1,000, 5,823 to 9,999, and 11,681to12,000 were not used)
    - 2 - 12,001-18,320 (1894-1898; numbers 12,842-13,000 were not used)
    - 3 - 18,321-24,655 (1898-1902)
    - 4 - 24,656-30,990 (1902-1905)
    - 5 - 30,991-37,325 (1905-1907)
    - 6 - 37,326-43,590 (1907-1908)
    - 7 - 43,592-50,205 (1908-1909)
    - 8 - 50,206-56,540 (1909-1911)
    - 9 - 56,541-62,875 (1911-1912)
    - 10 - 62,876-69,210 (1912-1913)
    - 11 - 69,211-75,545 (1913-1914)
    - 12 - 75,546-81,880 (1914-1918)
    - 13 - 81,881-88,285 (1918)
    - 14 - 88,286-90,280 (1918; also includes U.S.A., Sheppard estimate, Rice, Tracy, encased postage stamps)
    - 15 - 90,281-93,850 (1918-1920; also includes Transylvania, Russia, Spanish Mexico)
    - 16 - 93,851-100,815 (1920)
    - 17 - 100,816-107,780 (1920-1921)
    - 18 - 107,781-112,995 (1921)
    - 19 - 112,996-118,210 (1921-1922)
    - 20 - 118,211-123,391 (1922)
    - 21 - 123,426-128,606 (1922-1923)
    - 22 - 128,776-134,715 (1923-1925)
    - 23 - 134,716-137,360 (1925)
  - Extra (Ex) Ledgers
      nnan0034/c_43fd379d32f05456deaed1143e929198
    - Ex1 - 4,716-14,619 (a photocopy is also available)
    - Ex2 - 15,159-21,528 (a photocopy is also available)
    - Ex3 - 21,528-29,560
    - Ex4 - 29,560-36,731 (includes 5184)
  - Chicago Coin Company (Ch) Ledgers
      nnan0034/c_3dd9a85bfeaec5f003fdc82356199375
    - Ch1 - 1-3928
    - Ch2 - 3929-4460 and 30001-31809 (Allenberg collection)
    - Ch3 - Chicago Coin Company Inventory, Book #193 - 30,001-31,809 (2 copies)
    - Ch4 - Chicago Coin Company, Collection B (2 copies)
  - Numbers not in V.M.B.'s journals (NiJ) Ledgers
      nnan0034/c_5f413a88189fd03e1055f1e1c7ece34f
    - NiJ - 150,000-150,194; 350,000-353,075
    - NiJ - 353,077-360,106
    - NiJ? - Various U.S.A.
  - Place (Pla) - coins categorized by place of origin
      nnan0034/c_0b266145c1d95b2fef7d1d1cfa74249d
    - Pla 1 - mostly ca. 12000-26000